

Profile

I am a graduating senior at George Washington University studying Biological Anthropology and Journalism. Currently conducting research with the GW Life History and Skeletal Biology Lab on Virunga Mountain Gorilla feeding behavior. Museum internship experience with writing public-facing articles related to the anthropological and biological fields.

Links

LinkedIn

Skills

- Computer: MS Office, RStudio, Google Drive, Presentation tools.
- · BORIS Coding Software
- PastPerfect Musem Software
- AP Style and Research Skills
- · Manuscript and Grant Writing
- Organic Lab Procedure
- Museum Cataloging and Exhibit Design

Activites / Interests

GWU Circle K Service Organization

 Active in planning and participation in service events and projects in the DC area.

Dysautonomia Advocacy

 Met with members of Congress to advocate for increased funding for autonomic disorders research.

Interests

 Vocalist with vocal training; pianist with original works; enjoy international travel, cooking, and music

Emma Saaty

Biological Anthropology and Science lournalism Student

Phone 571-428-9870

Email emma@saaty.com

LocationWashington, DC

Employment History

Undergraduate Lab Researcher

Sept 2021 - Present

GW Center for the Advanced Study of Human Paleobiology

Washington, DC

Selected as an undergraduate research assistant at the GW Life History and Skeletal Biology Lab. Experience with behavioral and bone microanatomy research on Virunga mountain gorillas. Conducting senior thesis research on gorilla feeding behavior. Skills: grant and manuscript writing, BORIS coding software, organic lab procedure.

Smithsonian CFCH Intern

May 2022 - Sept 2022

Smithsonian Institution Center for Folklife and Cultural Heritage

Washington, DC

Worked with the Smithsonian Center for Folklife and Cultural Heritage to curate and run the accessibility experience at the folklife festival. Experience working with and writing about cultural panelists and festival attendees, and overseeing a group of volunteers.

Collections Management Intern

May 2021 - Sept 2021

Lee-Fendall House Museum & Garden

Alexandria, VA

Led the project of cataloging, preserving, and rehousing the entire textile collection of over 300 artifacts, working with PastPerfect software. Assisted in the research, interpretive documentation, and execution of exhibits.

Field and Lab Intern

Jan 2019 - Sept 2019

Fairfax C.A.R.T. Archaeology

Fairfax, VA

Worked alongside archaeologists in both the field and the lab excavating, cataloging, and writing reports. Wrote article for C.A.R.T. Archaeology website and a stoneware cataloging guide.

Education

George Washington University

Sept 2019 - May 2023

Bachelor of Science Candidate in Biological Anthropology Minors in Journalism and Biology GPA: 4.0, Dean's List, Presidential Scholarship. Washington, DC

McLean High School

Sept 2014 - June 2018

GPA: 4.0, National Honor Society, National English Honor Society, Virginia Department of Education Advanced Diploma with Governors Seal.

McLean, VA

Organizations

Treasurer and Financial Officer

Sept 2020 - Present

GWU Delta Iota Gamma - Academic Anthropology Fraternity

Executive Board member tasked with managing the budget planning, purchase requests, and entire financial organization of the fraternity. Worked with trademark lawyers to obtain the rights to found a national DIG chapter.